The wrong man. In the wrong place. At the right time.
Good Morning, Vietnam is a comedy, drama, war film directed by Barry Levinson.
A disk jockey goes to Vietnam to work for the Armed Forces Radio Service.
While he becomes popular among the troops, his
superiors disapprove of his humor.
Adrian Cronauer, played by Robin Williams.
Edward Garlick, played by Forest Whitaker.
Tuan, played by Tom T. Tran.
Trinh, played by Chintara Sukapatana.
Lt. Steven Hauk, played by Bruno Kirby.
Marty Lee Dreiwitz, played by Robert Wuhl.
Good Morning, Vietnam is a 1987 American war comedy drama film
written by Mitch Markowitz and directed by Barry Levinson.
Set in Saigon in 1965, during the Vietnam War, the film stars Robin Williams as an Armed Forces Radio Service (AFRS) DJ who
proves hugely popular with the troops, but infuriates his superiors with what they call his "irreverent tendency".
The story is loosely based on the experiences of AFRS DJ Adrian Cronauer.
Most of Williams's performances portraying Cronauer's
radio broadcasts were improvisations.
The film was released by Buena Vista Pictures (under its Touchstone Pictures banner) to critical and commercial success; for his work in the film, Williams won a Golden Globe Award
for Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy, and was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Actor and a BAFTA Award for Best Actor in a Leading Role.
In 2000, the film ranked number 100 on the American Film Institute's "100 Years...100 Laughs"
list, containing 100 movies considered the funniest movies in American cinema.
The film explores themes of dying and death, vietnam
war, rock 'n' roll, vietnam, vietcong.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.